Guide to the Urban League of Pittsburgh Records, 1915-1963 AIS.1981.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Government Bodies, VII.
  - Pennsylvania, 2.
    - Department of Public Assistance (Box 10, Folder 445)
    - Program of Child Welfare, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 446)
    - Display and Sale of Firearms, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 447)
- Reports, Studies and Theses, VIII.
  Series VIII, Reports, Studies, and Theses, were created by the Urban League of Pittsburgh, Urban League Fellows, and outside organizations. The subjects covered are education, employment, and African-American life from 1906-1950.
  - Reports and Studies, 1.
    - "Relation of Negro to Unemployment in Food Industry", by R. Maurice Moss, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 448)
    - CWA Project "Survey of Industrial Relationships of Negro Workers", 1934 (Box 10, Folder 449)
    - CWA Project Correspondence, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 450)
    - Survey of Negro Employment Domestic Employment in Pittsburgh, Correspondence. Includes statistical report of the Allegheny Emergency Committee, 1931-1935 (Box 10, Folder 451)
    - NYA "Survey of Negro Religious Life", 1935 (Box 10, Folder 452)
    - "Notes on Negro Life" by Reginald A. Johnson, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 453)
    - "Negro as consumers and Consumer Pressure for Jobs", 1939 (Box 10, Folder 454)
    - "Guiding Youth Toward Tomorrows Jobs", conducted jointly by the Urban League of Pgh. and the St. Cyprian Consistory #4 of Pgh., 1953 (Box 10, Folder 455)
    - "Study of 200 Negro Prisoners in the Western Penitentiary" by Ira De A Reid, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 456)
    - "Recent Studies Conclusions Pertinent to Negro Problems," prepared by Charles S. Johnson, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 457)
    - White Plains Survey, Correspondence, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 458)
    - Woofter Summary and Recommendations, Study of the Economic Status of the Negro, prepared by T. J. Woofter, Jr., 1930 (Box 10, Folder 459)
    - "Study of the Economic Status of the Negro" by T. J. Woofter, Jr., 1930 (Box 10, Folder 460)
    - "The Adult and Female Offenders in New York", 1906-1910 (Box 10, Folder 461)
    - "Our Colored Folks of Nassau and Suffolk Counties, Long Island, New York, by R. Maurice Moss, 1920-1930 (Box 10, Folder 462)
    - Survey of Pittsburgh Public Schools by a Special Commission appointed by the Board of Public Education, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 463)
    - Theses written in the Division of Social Work, School of Applied Social Sciences of the University of Pittsburgh, 1936-1950 (Box 10, Folder 464)
    - "Survey of Negro Population of Grand Rapid, Michigan", 1928 (Box 10, Folder 465)
    - "The Negro in Pittsburgh Industries" by C. Gould, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 466)
    - "The Negro Worker in Pittsburgh" by Abram Lincoln Harris, Jr., M.A., University of Pgh., 1924 (Box 10, Folder 467)
    - "Race Relations on South Side as seen through Brashear Settlement", by Pauline Redmond, M.A., Univ. of Pgh., 1936 (Box 10, Folder 468)
  - Theses, 2.
    - "Occupational Status of Negro in Iron and Steel Industry Pittsburgh and environs by F. Alden Wilson. Submitted to the Bur. of Bus. Res., Univ. of Pgh., 1934 (Box 10, Folder 469)
    - "Juvenile Delinquency in Restricted Area of Pittsburgh" by Elsie Rosalia Clarke, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 470)
    - "Baker Personnel Administration with Reference to Negro Labor" by James H. Baker, Jr., M.A., Univ. of Pgh., 1929 (Box 10, Folder 471)
- Photographs, ca. 1920's-1950's; IX.
  Series IX, Photographs, depict activities and prominent people of the Urban League circa 1920's-1950's. Photographs were separated from general collection and are housed in the media room at the Archives Service Center. A sample of photographic images from this collection have been digitized and are available for online research. The images depict housing and working conditions for black employees at Camp James Weldon and show group portraits taken at conventions and youth conferences from 1923-1958.
  - Activities (Box 10, Folder 475)
  - 30th Anniversary, December, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 476)
  - Annual Meetings, 1939-1958 (Box 10, Folder 477-481)
  - Annual Report Cover, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 482)
  - Apprenticeship Recognition Ceremony, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 483)
  - ARMCO (Box 10, Folder 484)
  - Barton, Thomas E., Plaque (Box 10, Folder 485)
  - Business Establishment Store (Box 10, Folder 486)
  - Camp James Weldon Johnson (Box 10, Folder 487)
  - Career Conference (Box 10, Folder 488)
  - Career Conference Neighborhoods (Box 10, Folder 489)
  - Carnegie Steel Co. (Box 10, Folder 490)
  - Cherry, Florence A. (Box 10, Folder 491)
  - Community Choir (Box 10, Folder 492)
  - Darnley, Samuel, Meeting (Box 10, Folder 493)
  - Davis Home Day Nursery for Colored Children (Box 10, Folder 494)
  - Ethran Temple (Box 10, Folder 495)
  - Equal Opportunity Day Observance, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 496)
  - Exhibits (Box 10, Folder 497)
  - FEPC Institute (Box 10, Folder 498)
  - FEPC Signing (Box 10, Folder 499)
  - Fellows, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 500)
  - Fitch, T.S. (Box 10, Folder 501)
  - Foy, Fred C. (Box 10, Folder 502)
  - Guild Ball, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 503)
  - High Doris, Secretary of the Year, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 504)
  - Home for the Aged and Infirm Colored Women (Box 10, Folder 505)
  - Housing (Box 10, Folder 506)
  - Housing, Penn Twp. (Box 10, Folder 507)
  - Individuals (Box 10, Folder 508)
  - Industrial Workers (Box 10, Folder 509)
  - Highland Park Pool (Box 10, Folder 510)
  - Joint Meeting, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 511)
  - Modern Land Improvement Co. (Box 10, Folder 512)
  - Monticello Street (Box 10, Folder 513)
  - Morrow, J.J. (Box 10, Folder 514)
  - National Urban League Headquarters Building (Box 10, Folder 515)
  - National Youth Association (Box 10, Folder 516)
  - Neighborhood Party, Sept. 9, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 517)
  - Urban League Officers (Box 10, Folder 518)
  - Urban League Organization (Box 10, Folder 519)
  - Organizations (Box 10, Folder 520)
  - Philadelphia Co. Veterans, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 521)
  - Pgh. Courier Employees and Press Operation (Box 10, Folder 522)
  - Rauh and Walk Shirt Factory (Box 10, Folder 523)
  - Schools (Box 10, Folder 524)
  - Sixth Mt. Zion Church (Box 10, Folder 525)
  - Trinity Church (Box 10, Folder 526)
  - Urban League Staff (Box 10, Folder 527)
  - Urban League Streetcar (Box 10, Folder 528)
  - Urban League Meeting Chicago Detroit, 1919-1921 (Box 10, Folder 529)
  - Urban League Meeting Richmond, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 530)
  - Urban League Meeting Pittsburgh, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 531)
  - Urban League Meeting, St. Louis, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 532)
  - Urban Renewal Institute, June 7,8, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 533)
  - YMCA (Box 10, Folder 534)
  - Dr. Marichal Neil E. Young (Box 10, Folder 535)
  - Youngstown Sheet and Tube Co. (Box 10, Folder 536)
  - Youth Conference for Vocational Opportunity (Box 10, Folder 537)
  - Youth Council (Box 10, Folder 538)
  - Uncategorized (Box 10, Folder 539)
  - Negatives Uncategorized (Box 10, Folder 540)
  - Urban League National Meetings, 1930-1948 (Box 10, Folder 541)
  - Johnson, Luther H., Photographer photos by LHJ (Box 10, Folder 542)
  - Urban League Community Choir (Box 10, Folder 543)
  - Photo: Uncategorized (Box 10, Folder 544)
  - Oversized
    - Picture of the National Urban League meetings-Buffalo, 1930; 1. (Map-case 7, Drawer 5)
    - Pictures of N.U.L meetings-Minneapolis, 1931; 2.
    - Pictures of N.U.L. meetings- Pittsburgh, 1933; 3.
    - Pictures of N.U.L. meetings- St. Louis, 1948; 4.
    - Pictures by Luther H. Johnson, F.F.B., 5.
    - Pictures of Urban League Community Choir, F.F.C., 6.
    - Associated Pictures, F.F.D., 7.